(847) 691-0246

https://github.com/alexcroitoru

SUMMARY

Analyst with proven technical and leadership aptitude. I have experience developing automated technology solutions to support the reporting needs of an organization. Well versed in partnering with key stakeholders to define needs and create technical designs to support those needs. I possess strong proficiency in ETL, data scrubbing and visualization which includes the use of Python, SQL, Power BI as primary languages among others.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python; R; SQL; SAS;

Tools: Power BI; Tableau; OlikView; Agile; Project Management (Atlassian, Clarity); Microsoft Office

WORK EXPERIENCE

AbbVie, Lake Bluff, IL

Systems Analyst – Global Trade Compliance

October 2021-Present

- Established within the Global Trade Organization overseeing support of business worth \$20MM. Engaged in SAP
 initiatives inside the Free Trade Zone market through management of application portfolio and delivery of
 enhancements on Agile scale
- Co-leading an initiative to migrate and re-platform a critical component of an acquisition's manufacturing operation to company standards with no impact to services offered on a global scale
- Directing business application implementation, management, and training for 500+ users achieving on-time delivery (100% milestones met on time) and budget expectations (\$500K) for the organization

Business Systems Analyst - Enterprise Applications - Finance Systems

July 2018-March 2022

- Worked within the Finance Function to implement automations, build visualizations for the business unit, and support expansion and acquisition projects for the organization
- Recognized for work on implementing an automation to detect fraud within employee Purchase Orders for the US affiliate, in current use with 97% success rate
- Drove effort to build visualizations on company sales by division utilized at the VP level of a Fortune 100 company
- Automated multiple organizational processes, driving average hard savings of ~\$100K and 500 employee hours.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Volatile Stocks Analysis | https://github.com/alexcroitoru/FinTech-Project-2

September 2021-Present

- Create a trading algorithm for mid / large cap stocks implementing ML and sentiment analysis
- Built API script to program Reddit Stock screener that would predict what stocks would be good to trade (long, short, options) for a period of 2 days
- Used Python for ML and sentiment analysis

Housing Market Analysis | https://github.com/alexcroitoru/Housing-Price-Prediction-and-Analysis

July 2021

- Calculate housing price MoM growth rates before 2019 and after 2021 with Quandl's state dataset broken into four regions
- Created a linear regression model to predict housing prices for our 4 predefined regions
- Utilized Python and SQL to sequester and wrangle our data

EDUCATION

Northwestern University

Certificate Course in Fintech

April 2021-October 2021

24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in VBA, Python, SQL, Big Data, Ethereum, Blockchain, and Machine Learning

Loyola University Chicago

Masters of Science in Statistics

May 2019